Michael Wester

(414) 380-3555 | mpwester@gmail.com

Software Engineer with over 13 years of professional experience in all aspects of the software development lifecycle. Range of experiences in green field projects, legacy applications, lightweight RESTful API's, Microservice based applications and stand-alone front-end clients. Proven leader, mentor, advocate and contributor to all aspects of software development.

Technical Expertise/Skills

Programming frameworks: Angular, Typescript, C#, React, Express, GraphQL

Testing frameworks: Jasmine, Jest, MSTest, XUnit, Selenium

Databases: SQL Server, Oracle, Redis, Cosmos DB, MongoDB, RedShift, Postgres, Snowflake, Gremlin

Cloud Services: Microsoft Azure and AWS

Tools: Azure Pipelines, AngularCLI, CircleCI, Octopus, JIRA, Jenkins, Github Workflows

Professional Experience

The Predictive Index, Remote Senior Software Engineer – Inspire 2.0

Oct 2021 - Nov 2022 Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

Inspire 2.0 initiative to reinvent the Inspire solution as a whole. In addition to a new modern version of the Inspire frontend, this is a redesign of the entire product offering. The main goal of Inspire offering is to build strong work relationships amongst team members. Currently, it is mostly used by leadership with the redesign attempting to increase involvement by employee's levels of the company.

- Initial creation/setup of Angular frontend project, Jest testing and Linting.
- Initial setup of tooling JIRA, CircleCI and Git repository.
- Lead frontend developer for the Product.

Lead Engineer - Global Experience

May 2022 – Oct 2022

Global Experience initiative that consists of a team of engineers, a product designer, and a product manager to standardize UI components and user experience of the Predictive Index suite. This initiative consists of building a new Angular consumable library for other modules/micro-frontends to consume.

- Initial library setup and integration with Storybook (3rd party tool).
- Integrate Angular Materials to replace existing infrastructure.
- Setup contribution guide allowing organization wide contribution.
- Direct manager of 3 direct reports.

Senior Software Engineer - Global Feature\Global Experience

Oct 2021 – May 2022

Global Feature initiative was created to manage global standardizations for backend microservices. Global Features focus managing permissions/access across all microservices as a part of the applications in the PI Suite. This initiative was a complete redesign of the permissions system from the ground up. Global Experience is attempting to integrate Angular Martials and standardize UI components across the PI Suite.

- Assisted in efforts modernizing the Hire and Design redesign and implementations.
- Assisted in the implement new permission control system switching from RBAC to ABAC
- Member of Frontend Advisory board and Internal committees.

Michael Wester

(414) 380-3555 | mpwester@gmail.com

GoPuff, Remote Feb 2021 – Oct 2020

Software Engineer II - Forecasting Engineering

Forecasting Engineering initiative is designed to better forecast workload/orders helping to manage and predict resources needed to keep up with guaranteed delivery times. Developing a new Full Stack React/Express/GraphQL application deployed in a Docker container. The Forecasting application is designed to take the current manual processes with multiple variations and standardize metrics across the organization.

- Learning and developing best practices for new React/GraphQL development.
- Developed numerous styled components to bring consistent feel to the new application.
- Setup base infrastructure for new development, builds, release and standalone instances.

InvestCloud (formerly Advicent), Milwaukee, WI Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2019 – Jun 2020

Guided Retirement, a greenfield front-end project, application provides a quick overview and basic insight from Financial Advisors to their end clients about retirement planning. The Essentials project, a greenfield full stack project, provides a more robust solution allowing for a larger customer base to access great financial planning. Both solutions utilized an Angular frontend communicating with RestFUL micro service-based backend. Both are fully built and deployed utilizing Azure Pipelines and docker containers.

- One of 4 required Angular developers pull request approvers, ensuring quality code.
- Started the new Essentials Angular Front-end project from scratch.
- Developed and released two new greenfield applications.
- Functioned as team lead for 3 software engineers, 1 QA engineer and 1 automation engineer.

Finastra (formerly D+H), Mequon, WI Software Engineer

May 2016 - Jul 2019 Sep 2017 - Jul 2019

Point-of-Sale Mortgage system development engineer, enhancing the legacy application providing banks with a SaaS solution, enabling them the ability to provide and process mortgage applications online.

- Implemented features to comply with ADA (American Disability Act) in association with WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines).
- Implemented integration with 3rd party applications to provide integrations for mortgage options and rates.
- Transitioned from aging TFS infrastructure to decentralized VSTS with Git hosted on top.
- Transitioned to modern technologies and best practices.

Software Engineer - Dev Lead

May 2016 - Sep 2017

Development Lead of a small team, 3 software engineers, 2 QA engineers, 3 offshore-software engineers), on a new green field product, NLP (New Lending Platform). Composed of a Razer MVC/Angular 4 front-end paired with C# .NET backend API and being deployed utilizing Microsoft Azure and Octopus.

- Gatekeeper for pull request changes into the main branch to ensure best practices and code quality.
- Developed multiple components and services to be consumed by our SPA and PWA.
- Implemented Angular animations to provide a stimulating overall User Experience.
- Implemented a new Angular Front end from beta to release candidate ending in Angular 4.

Michael Wester

(414) 380-3555 | mpwester@gmail.com

Blue Yonder (formerly JDA), Waukesha, WI Senior Consulting Software Engineer

May 2015 - Apr2016

Implantation Service - Developmental Services Engineer addressing identified gaps between our core software platform and the customer needs. Frequently requested gaps by multiple customers were worked to implement features inside of the core product warehouse management suite in addition to specific customers.

- Implement Voice enhancements introduced to the core product.
- Lead efforts collaborating with customers directly to meet their needs.
- Provided on-site support during customer go-lives to ensure the system is meeting the customer needs.

Iptor (formerly IBS AB), Brookfield, WI Software Developer

Nov 2013 – May 2015

Software development engineer looking to modernize the current Dynaman application from VB .NET monolithic application to AngularJS and C# API based application. Also was selected to spearhead a project to modernize and create integrations with 3rd party applications replacing SSIS with Java RESTful/SOAP web services.

- Developed Entity Framework RESTful API's for integration with internal and external systems.
- Implemented SOAP base Web Services for 3rd party integrations with the WMS.
- Helped lead development efforts modify core applications for S tier customers.

Blue Yonder (previously JDA previously RedPrairie), Waukesha, WI Dec 2009 – Nov 2013 Software Architect Intern/Senior Software Engineer/Technical Consultant Intermediate

Product Development Software Architect Intern working on new features and bug issues for our core product. Transitioned full time software engineer in our implementation services department and assisted in project implementations collaborating directly with customers to identify gaps between our product and their needs.

- Implemented new features to provide threaded session expiration in our core product.
- Worked on Johnson & Johnson, Georgia Pacific, Valspar and lead development efforts for MDL.
- Provided Analysis, Design, Implementation and Support for different phases of projects.

Education

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science